Finding Aid for Herbert C. and Louise C. Youtie papers, 1921-1986
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Herbert C. and Louise C. Youtie papers
1921-1986
Youtie, Herbert Chayyim, 1904-1980.
2014083 Aa 2
Herbert C. Youtie was a research professor of Papyrology and associate professor of Greek at the University of Michigan. Louise C. Youtie was a scholar of Greek and Papyrology. The Youties' expertise in the field of papyrology was internationally renowned. Their papers document their work transcribing, studying, and interpreting script found in papyri and ostraka. Materials include correspondence, publication drafts, research paperwork, and photographs of papyri.
8 linear feet
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The records (donor no. 10948 ) were received in 2013 from the Papyrology Collection
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open without restriction.
A detailed index of collection contents in spreadsheet form was prepared by and received from the University of Michigan Papyrology Collection. It provides item level description of materials and references scans made by the unit. [View index]
Herbert Chayyim Youtie was born in 1904 in Atlantic City, New Jersey where he lived until he graduated from high school. He went on to the University of Cincinnati where he completed a Bachelor of Arts in 1927. Youtie then moved to New York where he pursued an M. A. at Columbia University. After receiving his Masters of Arts in 1928, he also received degrees from European institutions; a diploma from L'Institut Catholique de Paris in 1929.
In 1929 Youtie started working at the University of Michigan as a Research Assistant in Papyrology. In 1930 he was made Instructor of Greek. By 1932 he had been promoted to Research Associate in Papyrology, became Assistant Professor in 1938, Associate Professor in 1944 and Research Professor of Papyrology by 1946.
Youtie excelled in his teaching, and particularly in his transcription and study of papyri from Greco-Roman Egypt. His work also entailed deciphering ostraka and some Coptic script in either papyri or ostraka. The quality of his work was recognized early in his career not only in Michigan but internationally. He was often consulted by colleagues and institutions locally and internationally regarding transcriptions. He came to be regarded as an authority in the field of papyrology. Youtie's work is also reflected in his multiple publications, resulting from his transcription work and about the discipline of papyrology itself. During his career he worked on over 110 publications, among which the following seminal books are found; The Papyrologist: Artificer of Fact and Text and Context in Transcribing Papyri.
Youtie's work was recognized through a University of Michigan Henry Russel Award and a Guggenheim Fellowship in 1957. He was Russel lecturer in 1962 and awarded the Distinguished Faculty Achievement Award in 1974. In 1969 the University of Cologne conferred an honorary doctoral degree, an honor usually reserved for German citizens. The Association Internationale des Papyrologues named Youtie Président d'Honneur and he was chosen as a Corresponding Fellow by the British Academy. At the time of his retirement from the University of Michigan, in 1975, Youtie was named Research Professor Emeritus of Papyrology. In 1976, his work was once more recognized when colleagues presented him with Collectanea Papyrologica a series of texts published in his honor and edited by Ann Ellis Hanson. Youtie died in 1980.
Louise Carolyn Canberg was a native of Grand Rapids, Michigan where she was born on August 30, 1909. She pursued an undergraduate degree in Greek at the University of Michigan, which she completed in 1932. A year later, in June 1933, she received a Master's of Arts from the same institution. Louise married Professor Herbert C. Youtie in 1934.
Louise C. Youtie worked in the Papyrology Collection at the University of Michigan's Graduate Library for sixty two years transcribing Greek script found in papyri from the extensive collections at the University. She was known as the unofficial overseer of the Papyrology Collection. Her expertise is reflected in her research and bibliography, some of which focused on medical classical texts. One of her great contributions to papyrology and the history of medicine was her translation, commentary and publication of The Michigan Medical Codex (P.Mich. 758 = P.Mich.Inv. 21) in 1996. Along with her husband, she was often consulted by national and international colleagues in the field about papyri transcription and interpretation.
Louise C. Youtie died in 2004 after contributing much to the field of papyrology and the University of Michigan's Papyrology Collection.
The Herbert C. Youtie series, 1932 -- 1979 (5 linear feet) documents his work transcribing, studying, and interpreting ancient Greek & Coptic script found in papyri and ostraka. The contents of this series also contain paperwork with his research, writing, and correspondence. Materials include photograph prints of papyri which he used for his work. Also found here are his professional correspondence, publication drafts, commentaries, final copies, and transcripts. The content is divided into four sub-series: Papyri, Writings and Publications, Correspondence, and Transcriptions and Notes. The arrangement of materials, as they were received from the University of Michigan Papyrology Collection, has been retained.
Additional descriptive information on folder contents is found in the collection spreadsheets supplied by the University of Michigan Papyrology Collection. The ordering of the material in this collection reflects the manner in which it was organized and received.
Subjects:
Greek language--Texts.; Manuscripts, Greek (Papyri); Ostraka.; Youtie, Herbert Chayyim, 1904-1980.; Youtie, Louise C. (Louise Canberg); University of Michigan. Library.
- Youtie Index
  The Youtie Index series, 2010 (156.1KB) contains a detailed index of collection contents in spreadsheet form prepared by and received from the University of Michigan Papyrology Collection. It provides item level description of materials and references scans made by the unit.
  - H.C. and L.C. Youtie Archive Index
- Herbert C. Youtie
  - Papyri
    The Papyri sub-series (2 linear feet) This sub-series includes black and white photographs of papyri along with transcriptions, notes, and some correspondence for these. Papyri referenced include P.Cair.Isid., P.Panop.I., P.Cairo, P.Mert., P.Princeton, P.Fuad., P.Koln., P.Thead., P.Mich., and P.Petaus. Contents also include some photographic negatives, tracings, and charts.
    - P.Cair.Isid. 1-3 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - P.Cair.Isid. 4 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - P.Cair.Isid. 5 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - P.Cair.Isid. 6 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - P.Cair.Isid. 8 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - P.Cair.Isid. 9 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - P.Cair.Isid. 10 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - P.Cair.Isid. 11-12 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - P.Cair.Isid. 13 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - P.Cair.Isid. 14-15 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - P.Cair.Isid. 18-20 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - P.Cair.Isid. 21 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - P.Cair.Isid. 22-29 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - P.Cair.Isid. 30-34 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - P.Cair.Isid. 35-39 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - P.Cair.Isid. 40-44 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - P.Cair.Isid. 45-46 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - P.Cair.Isid. 47 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - P.Cair.Isid. 48-49 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - P.Cair.Isid. 50 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - P.Cair.Isid. 51-55 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - P.Cair.Isid. 56-61 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - P.Cair.Isid. 62 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - P.Cair.Isid. 63 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - P.Cair.Isid. 65-67 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - P.Cair.Isid. 68 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - P.Cair.Isid. 69-72 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - P.Cair.Isid. 73 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - P.Cair.Isid. 74, 2 folders (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - P.Cair.Isid. 75-80 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - P.Cair.Isid. 81-85 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - P.Cair.Isid. 86-90 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - P.Cair.Isid. 91-95 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - P.Cair.Isid. 96-100 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - P.Cair.Isid. 101-105 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - P.Cair.Isid. 106-110 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - P.Cair.Isid. 111-115 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - P.Cair.Isid. 116-120 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - P.Cair.Isid. 121-125 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - P.Cair.Isid. 126 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - P.Cair.Isid. 127-130 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - P.Cair.Isid. 131-134 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - P.Cair.Isid. 135 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - P.Cair.Isid. 136-137 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - P.Cair.Isid. 138 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - P.Cair.Isid. 139 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - P.Cair.Isid. 140 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - P.Cair.Isid. 141 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - P.Cair.Isid. 142 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - P.Cair.Isid. 143-144 (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - P.Cair.Isid. 145 (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - P.Cair.Isid. 146 (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - P.Cair.Isid. O. Gueraud notes and correspondence (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - P.Cair.Isid. notes and correspondence miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - P.Panop. I 1-14 photographs (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - P.Panop. I 15-19 photographs (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - P.Panop. I 15-19 notes, correspondence, ms. (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - P.Panop. III 20-31 photographs (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - P.Panop. III 20 notes (Box 1, Folder 59)
    - P.Panop. III 21 (Box 1, Folder 60)
    - P.Panop. III 22 (Box 1, Folder 61)
    - P.Panop. III 23-24 (Box 1, Folder 62)
    - P.Panop. III 25 (Box 1, Folder 63)
    - P.Panop. III 26 (Box 1, Folder 64)
    - P.Panop. III 27 (Box 1, Folder 65)
    - P.Panop. III 28 (Box 1, Folder 66)
    - P.Panop. III 29 (Box 1, Folder 67)
    - P.Panop. III 30 (Box 1, Folder 68)
    - P.Panop. III 31 (Box 1, Folder 69)
    - P.Mich.IV 223 coll. 3-20: photos (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - P.Mich.IV 223 coll. 21-40: photos (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - P.Mich.IV 223 coll. 41-60: photos (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - P.Mich.IV 223 coll. 61-80: photos (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - P.Mich.IV 223 coll. 81-99: photos (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - P.Mich.IV 223 coll. 101-103; fr. 1-11; verso, col. 35: photos 6 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - P.Mich.IV 223 negatives I coll. 101-103; fr 1-5 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - P.Mich.IV 223 negatives II fr. 6-11 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - P.Mich.IV 223: daily totals (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - P.Mich.IV 224 marginal totals (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - P.Mich.IV 224 daily totals (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - P.Mich.IV 225 daily totals (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - P.Mich.IV 357-363 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - P.Mich.IV 357-359 negatives (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - P.Mich.IV 360-363 negatives (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - P.Mich.IV 359-363 tracings (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - P.Mich.IV final totals (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - P.Mich.IV charts: geometria, groups of taxpayers, others (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Dike tax (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - P.Mich.IV land tax (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - P.Mich.IV notes (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - P.Mich.IV losses (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - P.Mich.IV obols (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - P.Mich.IV paleography, orthography, etc. (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - P.Mich.IV poll tax rates (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - P.Mich.IV notes 2 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - P.Mich.IV miscellaneous notes (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - P.Mich.IV symbolikon (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - P.Mich.IV typescript (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - P.Petaus 1-4 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - P.Petaus 5-8 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - P.Petaus 9-12 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - P.Petaus 13-16 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - P.Petaus 17-20 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - P.Petaus 21-24 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - P.Petaus 25-28 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - P.Petaus 29-32 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - P.Petaus 33-36 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - P.Petaus 37-40 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - P.Petaus 41-44 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - P.Petaus 45-48 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - P.Petaus 49-52 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - P.Petaus 53-56 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - P.Petaus 57-58 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - P.Petaus 59 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - P.Petaus 60 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - P.Petaus 61-63 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - P.Petaus 64-67 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - P.Petaus 68-71 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - P.Petaus 72-75 (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - P.Petaus 76-79 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - P.Petaus 80-83 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - P.Petaus 84-87 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - P.Petaus 88-91 (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - P.Petaus 92-95 (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - P.Petaus 96-99 (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - P.Petaus 100-103 (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - P.Petaus 104-107 (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - P.Petaus 108-111 (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - P.Petaus 112-115 (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - P.Petaus 116-119 (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - P.Petaus 120-123 (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - P.Petaus 124-127 (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - P.Petaus miscellaneous (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - P.Petaus index materials (Box 2, Folder 65)
    - P.Petaus inventories (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Writings and Publications
    The Writings and Publications sub-series (1 linear foot) contains drafts and notes about H.C. Youtie's published and unpublished papers as well as oral presentations.
    - AGRAMMATOS drafts: An Aspect of Greek Society in Egypt -- typescripts, proofs, ms. (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - AGRAMMATOS notes: illiteracy (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - AGRAMMATOS used material: standards of literacy (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - APATORES drafts: Law Vs. Custom in Roman Egypt-typescripts and ms. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - APATORES notes, materials (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - "Because they do not know letters..." notes and ms. (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - BRADEOS GRAPHON proofs and lectures: Between Literacy and Illiteracy (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - BRADEOS GRAPHON notes (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - PROSKUNEMA to Sarapis or Grenfell's Gift to Lumbroso: ms and drafts (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - PROSKUNEMA to Sarapis or Grenfell's Gift to Lumbroso: notes (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - A Note on Edson's Macedonica III proof and correspondence 11 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - A Point of Method notes and photos (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - A Point of Method photos (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - A Problem in Graeco-Roman Bookkeeping drafts (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Scriptiunculae offprints (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Scriptiunculae correspondence (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Scriptiunculae addenda et corrigenda to TAPA articles (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Scriptiunculae addenda et corrigenda to vol. I (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Scriptiunculae addenda et corrigenda to vol. II in progress (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Scriptiunculae addenda et corrigenda to vol. II final copy (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - The Textual Criticism of papyri 2nd ed. Drafts (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - The Textual Criticism of papyri 2nd ed. Materials (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - The Textual Criticism of papyri 2nd ed. Correspondence (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - HUPOGRAPHEUS drafts (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - HUPOGRAPHEUS notes (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Again P.IFAO 88 ms. and correspondence (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Monogamy and Polygamy in Graeco-Roman Egypt notes and typescript (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - On physicians in the papyri notes and ms (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - For Herb Paper's symposium typescript (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - For talk to Wegman's club notes and translations of various papyri (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - On Kelsey memoranda typescript [Russell Lecturers] (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Language and Texts conference: The Nature of Linguistic Evidence (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Correspondence
    The Correspondence sub-series (0.75 linear feet) consists of correspondence between Herbert C. Youtie and papyrology scholars. Correspondence usually includes transcriptions and notes on specific papyri. Papyri referenced include P.Berol., P.Mich., P.Oxy., P.Laur., among others.
    - Allison, Robert, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Aly, Zaki, 1953; undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Amundsen, Leiv, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Bagnall, Roger, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Borkowski, Zbigniew, 1973-1974 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Bowman, Alan, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Brashear, William, 1973-1974 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Browne, Gerald, 1971-1979 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Clarysse, Willy, 1974-1976 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Day, J., 1955 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Festugiere, A J, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Fink, Robert, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Foraboschi, Daniele, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Gallazzi, Claudio, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Gignac, Frank, 1972-1978 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Gilliam, Frank, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Goldstein, Jonathan, undated (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Gronewald, Michael, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Gueraud, Octave, 1939 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Gulezyan, H. Aram, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Heller, John, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Hombert, Marcel, 1949 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Johnson, Allan, 1943 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Jordan, D. R., 1973 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Kraemer, Casper, 1950 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Lewis, N., 1941-1978 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Maltomini, Franco, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Manfredi, M., 1970 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - McCarren, V., undated (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Merkelbach, Reinhold, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Modrzejewski, Joseph, 1969-1972 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Muller, W., 1970 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Neugebauer, O., 1941-1949 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Nock, Arthur D., 1943 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Oliver, J., 1979 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Page, D., 1973 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Parassoglou, George, 1973-1978 (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Parsons, Peter, 1963-1974 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Pintaudi, Rosario, 1974-1978; 2 folders (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Raschke, Manfred G., 1974 (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Rea, John, 1970-1972 (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Roberts, Colin, 1955-1970 (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Rupprecht, Hans Albert [folder P. Yale. Inv. 1729], 1979 (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - Samuel, Deborah [in sub, 1970-1978 (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - Schlaifer, Robert, 1941 (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - Schwartz, J., 1972 (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - Shelton, John, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 47)
    - Sijpesteijn, Piet, 1970-1979 (Box 4, Folder 48)
    - Smothers, Edgar, 1940 (Box 4, Folder 49)
    - Thomas, David, 1969-1970 (Box 4, Folder 50)
    - Traill, John, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 51)
    - Turner, Eric G., 1970 (Box 4, Folder 52)
    - Vandoni, Mariangela, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 53)
    - Welles, Bradford, 1940; 1960 (Box 4, Folder 54)
    - West, Louis, 1941 (Box 4, Folder 55)
    - Willis, William, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - Transcriptions and Notes
    Transcriptions and Notes sub-series (0.25 linear feet) includes notes and transcriptions of papyri and ostraka. Papyri referenced include P.Oxy, P.Mich, and NYU ostraka.
    - P.Mich. I 30b (Box 4, Folder 57)
    - P.Mich. II 126 (Box 4, Folder 58)
    - P.Mich. 129 (Shepherd of Hermas) manuscript collations --(part 1) (Box 4, Folder 59-1)
    - P.Mich. 129 (Shepherd of Hermas) notes (part 2) (Box 4, Folder 59-2)
    - P.Mich. III 214 notes and commentary (Box 4, Folder 60)
    - P.Mich. V 281 photograph (Box 4, Folder 61)
    - P.Mich. VI 434 transcript: revision (Box 4, Folder 62)
    - P.Mich.Michael 26 photograph (Box 4, Folder 63)
    - P.Mich.inv. 4800 Musurillo transcription, photograph, notes (Box 4, Folder 64)
    - O.Mich. I 180 (Box 4, Folder 65)
    - O.Mich. Various Dime finished transcripts (Box 4, Folder 66)
    - O.Mich. Various Karanis preliminary transcripts (Box 4, Folder 67)
    - O.Mich. Various purchased finished transcripts (Box 4, Folder 68)
    - BGU IX photos, notes on abbreviations, 1891 (Box 4, Folder 69)
    - P.Col.Zen.II 78 photographs (Box 4, Folder 70)
    - P.Col.Zen.II 90 photographs (Box 4, Folder 71)
    - P.Col.Zen. II 121 and 122 transcripts, correspondence 1933-34 (Box 4, Folder 72)
    - P.Fam.Tebt. 9 photos; publication with Y's notes; correspondence (Box 4, Folder 73)
    - P.Koln II 83 proofs from D. Hagedorn with Y's notes (Box 4, Folder 74)
    - P.LilleDem. 29 photostat of publication (Box 4, Folder 75)
    - P.Oxy. II 264 notes, transcripts (Box 4, Folder 76)
    - P.Oxy. XLII 3017, 3047, 3048, 3051 (Box 4, Folder 77)
    - P.Rob.inv. 35 (Box 4, Folder 78)
    - P.Stras. 301-310 offprint with publication with Y's notes (Box 4, Folder 79)
    - PSI 1414 (Box 4, Folder 80)
    - Coptic papyrus (Box 4, Folder 81)
    - NYU ostraka inv. 1-10 photos, transcripts, notes (Box 4, Folder 82)
    - NYU ostraka inv. 11-20 photos, transcripts, notes (Box 4, Folder 83)
    - NYU ostraka inv. 21-30 photos, transcripts, notes (Box 4, Folder 84)
    - NYU ostraka inv. 31-40 photos, transcripts, notes (Box 4, Folder 85)
    - NYU ostraka inv. 41-50 photos, transcripts, notes (Box 4, Folder 86)
    - NYU ostraka inv. 51-60 photos, transcripts, notes (Box 4, Folder 87)
    - NYU ostraka inv. 61-70 photos, transcripts, notes (Box 4, Folder 88)
    - NYU ostraka inv. 71-73 photos, transcripts, notes (Box 4, Folder 89)
    - NYU ostraka transcripts (Box 4, Folder 90)
    - NYU ostraka TARICHEUTES (Box 4, Folder 91)
    - NYU ostraka TOU AUTOU ETOUS abbreviation (Box 4, Folder 92)
    - NYU ostraka Kraemer notes, detail photographs (Box 4, Folder 93)
    - NYU ostraka Youtie miscellaneous notes (Box 4, Folder 94)
    - Sbaita ostraka photographs, articles (Box 4, Folder 95)
    - P.Bon. 24 photographs (Box 4, Folder 96)
  - Miscellaneous & Oversize
    Miscellaneous and Oversized Material sub-series (1 linear foot) contains correspondence, drafts, photographs and materials regarding unidentified papyri. Materials also include folders and mailing tubes containing facsimiles that were not scanned by the Papyrology Collection.
    - TAPA report on Householder and Prakken "A Ptolemaic Graffitto in New York", 1946 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - TAPA report on B. Welles "Garden of Ptolemagrius", 1947 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - TAPA report on Dr. Wolfe, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - TAPA report on D. Georgacas concerning, 1956 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - TAPA report on R. Shark "Three Inscriptions from Egypt", 1960; 1962 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - TAPA report on Dr. Wolff, Yale papyrus (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Notes on Bonner's Melito (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Notes on Post's reading of the Germanicus papyrus (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Notes on Miss Swiderek's paper (Studied for Eric Turner), 1962 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous notes (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous notes marked useless (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous notes marked can't use (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Papyrology course notes -- notes on procedure, goals, methods (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Papyrology course bibliography (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Letter to Michigan Daily re: Hatcher 807 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - S. Agrell article in Eranos 26 "Studies in Late Antique Letter (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Mysticism"
    - N. Lewis ASP article "Inventory of Compulsory Services in Ptolemaic and Roman Egypt", 1975 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - THEOI SOTERES dissertation chapter maybe by J.F. Oates (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - P.Mich. II 124 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - P.Mich. IV 223 coll. 12-17:enlarged photos (Box 5, Folder 20-1)
    - P.Mich. IV 223 coll. 12-17:enlarged negatives (Box 5, Folder 20-2)
    - P.Mich.inv. 2958 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - P.Oxy. 27122713 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - P.Petaus 27 and 31; 37, 48, 98; 47, 92, 93, 122 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - John Chrysostom on Acts XVI -- XVIII, XL (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - John Chrysostom homilies (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - John Chrysostom homilies (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - John Chrysostom homilies (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - John Chrysostom homilies (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - John Chrysostom homilies, miscellaneous church texts (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - John Chrysostom homily 27 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - John Chrysostom homilies (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - John Chrysostom homilies (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - John Chrysostom homilies (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - John Chrysostom (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - John Chrysostom homily 2 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - John Chrysostom homily 10 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - John Chrysostom, 2 folders (Box 5, Folder 12-13)
    - John Chrysostom 14 (Box 5, Tube 1)